ANISLEY SAEZ V.

anisleysv@gmail.com 786-608-2846 Houston, TX www.linkedin.com/in/anisleysv

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

Bilingual professional passionate about new technologies, fast learner with a can-do attitude and strong problem solving focus. 7+ years helping companies to get the most of technology by improving productive processes with software solutions and teaching professionals to develop the right technical skills. Well known for going the extra mile in my professional assignments. Bringing a unique perspective in the relation: clients needs -- technology -- solutions.

EDUCATION

MS in E-Learning, majoring in Educational Technology - 2014 BS in Information Technology, majoring in Computer Sciences - 2008

both titles earned at the University of Computer Sciences, Havana, Cuba (Named in Spanish: Universidad de las Ciencias Informáticas - www.uci.cu)

SKILLS

Competencies: fast learner, problem solving, communication, creative, analytical thinking, object oriented programming, web design, organize, teamwork, leadership, public speaking.

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JAVASCRIPT, JAVA, SQL.

Tools: Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Atom, Git, GitHub, Netbeans, Postgresql, Visual Paradigm. **Others:** Slack, UML, UI, JQuery, Bootstrap, Angular, AS-400, Moodle, Educational Technologies

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOUTHWEST KEY PROGRAMS - Houston, Texas USA

2017 - 2018

Seasonal teacher

- Teaching several subjects to a multicultural youth.
- Planning Project Based Learning creative activities with the educational department.
- Using software tools such ETO, Sharepoint, Relias Learning to improve work performance.

COSTEX TRACTOR PARTS - Miami, Florida USA

2016 - 2017

Office clerk | Shipping coordinator

- Collaborating with the Technology Department to review and develop reports AS-400. Reduced in 5% daily work efforts of shipping group due to the improvement of POE Reports Process.
- Managing a big database (enter, retrieve and remove data) with the AS-400 system.
- Developing multiple tasks in daily routine at a fast paced environment, including: data processing, mailing requests; matching, filing, faxing and scanning documents.

UNIVERSITY OF COMPUTER SCIENCES - Havana, Cuba

2008 - 2016

Software Engineer | Assistant professor (2014-2016)

- Working in CALINFOR project and developing programs, web UI, media resources, objects and learning assignments for Moodle: Dreamweaver, HTML, CSS.
- Leading a small team of professors for almost 2 years.
- Acting as technical consultor during the design and implementation of educational products.

• Teaching graduate programs and conducting researches in the area of Educational Technology.

Software Engineer | Instructor (2008-2014)

- Performing research and problem solving tasks in real world projects: ALFAOMEGA, MPPEU and GALM. (Please consult accomplishments section for more details)
- Teaching Computer Sciences in the disciplines of Software Engineering and Programming Techniques, involving: Algorithms, Object Oriented Programming, Netbeans, Java, Relational Databases Design, Triggers, Postgresql, SQL.

SELECTED ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Built my professional portfolio in 2018 and gained online visibility by learning how to use
 Adobe Creative Cloud (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign), Git, GitHub, Atom, HTML5, CSS3 and
 Javascript to design a brand and develop interactive websites from scratch. Pursuing an
 specialization in Web Development (Break Into Tech Blueprint) at SKILLCRUSH. Portfolio:
 https://www.asvweb.us
- Helped UCI project managers to meet deadlines and publish results in National and International
 events (please refer to linkedin profile, publications section), involving the successful coordination
 and follow up of professionals with different backgrounds and specializations:

CALINFOR (software engineer, specialist in Educational Technology)

2014 - 2016

- Deployed new technologies, with a pedagogical foundation, in the Institutional Learning Management System (Moodle) to improve the System of Learning Resources used to teach Relational Database Design to future software engineers.
- Written the results mentioned above as thesis and presented in the option to the Master's degree in eLearning. Technologies involved: Netbeans, Java, Postgresql, RDB, SQL.

MPPEU (software engineer, specialist in Educational Technology)

2011 - 2013

- Developed programs to compliment the function of the Educational Platform related to the use of e-books and e-readers.
- Supported the decision making process by providing a Technical report and a database with critical information for the development of the project. [Relational Database Design, Postgresql]

ALFAOMEGA (software engineer, specialist in Standards for Content Management) 2010 - 2011

- Helped to reach 100% customer satisfaction for the project first year milestones.
- Highly recognized personal performance in:
 - o selection of technologies and standards of content management for the platform.
 - team's technical instruction involving: SCORM, OOP, JAVA, Relational Database, SQL.

GALM (analyst, developer, QA management)

2007-2009

- Successfully developed the IDE Management Subsystem for Visual Interface Design (Picasso) by using Netbeans, C++, QT libraries, and the eXtreme Programming Methodology (pair programming).
- Written partial results as thesis and presented in the option to the Bachelor's degree.